FIDEL HDZ

PRIMARY SKILLS

- HTML
- · CSS / SCSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- ¡Query
- Angular
- Astro
- WordPress
- PHP
- UI Design
- · Graphic Design
- Branding & Marketing
- MySQL

SECONDARY SKILLS

- ReactJS
- NodeJS / NextJS
- Rest API
- GIT
- MongoDB
- Agile

EDUCATION

Systems Administrator Engineer

Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León (1992 - 1997)

PROFILE

Front-end developer with 14 years of experience. Highly skilled in jQuery, Angular, and TypeScript and have extensive experience working with national and American companies which helped improve my soft skills and English level.

UI developer with more than 20 years of experience (HTML5, CSS3, SASS, SCSS, JavaScript, and ActionScript). I won a couple of awards for design and animation using jQuery, JavaScript, and CSS.

WordPress developer with 12 years of experience (creating templates from scratch and plugins) while using PHP as the principal language.

UI/UX designer with more than 20 years of helping creative departments make their ideas a reality.

Branding consultant and logo designer focused on using my creativity to help small and medium size companies bring out the best of themselves. I won some awards for branding in Mexico and US.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALTIMETRIK MÉXICO, S.A. de C.V.

Period: JUL 2021 - JAN 2023

Worked with a few clients:

Citi Bank - I created the landing page and website for a new product for the US. We used reactJS creating components to re use it in other pages.

Ancestry - I helped to migrate the website content and landing pages from Magnolia to AEM and I have been part of the Marketing frontend team and we worked through AWS with WinOs installed.
Guaranteed Rate - My contribution was creating the UX Design and wireframes for the mobile app.

Altimetrik -In internal projects, I participated as UX & UI designer and created prototypes in Angular because the backend team wanted to test the calls to APIs and get the most real interactions with the Data Base for Altimetrik Mexico and Altimetrik International.

ReactJS JavaScript TypeScript HTML5 See SASS / SCSS CIT UI UI Design

UX UX Design

METAGENICS, INC.

Period: JAN 2019 - APR 2021

Role: Frontend Dev & UI/UX Designer

Role: Principal Engineer

- Created connections from CMS' API to feed the principal portal.
- Helped with design improvements for the web app.
- Did updates on the front end for the portal and the web app for different countries and dev environments.
- Participated in the development of the UI on a project to cast medical results on 4K TV.
- Helped the design team with my User Experience skills.
- Was part of the front-end team on the development of the web app for medical clinics with Angular and TypeScript.
- Created new screens for new processes on the web app as UI/UX designer. Used Adobe XD to create the screens and Adobe Illustrator for iconography and illustrations for some sections.

🗴 Angular 🔢 TypeScript 🥫 HTML5 🔝 SASS / SCSS 🏥 GIT 👿 UX Design 🚺 UI Design

Wynne Systems, LLC.

Period: AUG 2018 - JUL 2019

Role: UI Developer

- Worked on JSP files injecting jQuery to improve the web app and fixed bugs in the app.
- · Created functions on JS.
- Created and updated styles using SCSS.
- · Improved UI in different views.
- · Created layouts (UI) keeping the philosophy of "mobile first" in mind.
- Cleaned up code on JSP files.

TOOLS

- JIRA / ASANA
- · BitBucket / GitHub
- GitKraken
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- SketchApp
- Affinity Designer
- Affinity Publisher
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- · Visual Studio Code
- Procreate
- WordPress
- AEM

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

EXERTUS Marketing, LLC.

Period: SEP 2015 - JAN 2018

Role: Web and UI Developer

- · Built sites from design files (illustrator, photoshop, or sketchapp).
- Developed themes for WordPress (WP) to use on main websites.
- Generates templates for WP to implement for landing pages.
- Developed shortcodes to simplify writing articles for the main blog.
- · Had connections set up with web services (API) to work with jQuery.
- Created or edited WP plugins.
- Developed animations with CSS (or SCSS / SASS) or jQuery.
- Generated styles for responsive sites from the desktop version of the site.
- Developed mini web apps for sites like a signature generator for emails with the possibility to generate downloadable files.
- Connected websites forms with Campaign Monitor, PipeDrive and mailChimp services.
- · Generated icon fonts.
- · Developed templates in HubSpot to create Landing Pages.
- · Used GIT as Control Version Management.

Honored to have been part of the leadership committee board helping make decisions about whether some projects needed extra elements or if a team could help another on the different projects within the company.

As a team, won different web prizes for interaction, usability, and animations created with JS and CSS.



Sonata Services, S.A. de C.V.

Period: JAN 2014 - SEP 2015

Proud to be a former outsourcer for Creative Mob (a creative agency located in San Diego California), Taylor Made Company, and TicketBox.

Creative Mob - I worked with UI/UX and desktop and mobile layout (responsive).

- Built sites from mockups created on Adobe Illustrator or Adobe Photoshop).
- Developed themes for WP.
- Generated templates for WP to implement for landing pages.
- Had set up connections with web services (API) to work with jQuery or AngularJS.
- · Created or edited WP plugins.
- Developed animations with CSS (or SCSS / SASS) or ¡Query.
- Generated styles for responsive sites from the desktop version of the site.
- · Generated icon fonts.
- · Used GIT as Control Version Management.

Taylor Made - I created multiple screens using RoR, HTML, and SCSS.

TicketBox - I was responsible for creating views and screens in PHP, creating events and presales of tickets and poll systems for film studios such as Relativity Media, Lionsgate, Bad Robot, and Legendary for generating marketing tools to use in movie previews.



PayBook (startup)

Period: JUL 2012 - NOV 2013

Role: Frontend Developer

Role: Frontend Developer

I Was part of the first team of developers for the web application and was in charge of the front end.

- Built sites from mockups created on Adobe Illustrator or Adobe Photoshop.
- Started with jQuery when the project began to create the web app, which in the end was updated with AngularJS using the SPA implementation.
- · Had connections set up with API to work with jQuery or AngularJS.
- · Generated styles for the responsive web app.
- · Used GIT as Control Version Management.
- Created the most important feature that offered the possibility to upload documents, photos, and load tickets with pictures and took the information to convert it into text and split it into categories.





PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OFIK, S.A. de C.V.

Period: FEB 2009 - DEC 2011

Role: Ecommerce Manager

Was in charge of the department responsible for developing the principal website with a shopping cart. As a designer supported the marketing and sales departments by creating printed material.

- · Was responsible of the e-commerce department.
- · Was UI developer and graphic designer.
- Created a sub-site for another company called Linea Italia.
- Participated in projects alongside the CEO creating SaSS for manufacturing companies and adding my creativity skills and my expertise to projects as a developer with PHP and ColdFusion.
- Contributed to the creativity committee by creating ads and stands for the different office furniture expos in the country and abroad as the big expo of office furniture in China.

Coahuila Government

Period: MAY 2005 - DEC 2009

Role: Web Developer

- · Was responsible for authorizing and reviewing every portal of all government dependencies.
- Developed a CMS to feed the main portal, the state's history website, and the website for kids. The users could create articles with photos as news, update the content of the pages, and small quiz games for kids.
- Was the main portal developer creating the back office with PHP and MySQL, and using HTML, CSS, and jQuery to create the front end, which was created from scratch without any framework (only jQuery).
- Created some illustrations for the aforementioned kids' portal, which was developed in Adobe Flash using ActionScript, PHP, and MySQL.

PHP THIML5 CSS3 (jQuery UI UI Design

As Freelancer

Period: In the middle of the hiring process

Role: Web Developer and Graphic Designer

- Developed a lot of websites and web apps using a lot of tools, methodologies, and strategies to create amazing products.
- Created custom CMS with PHP and MySQL or customizing commercial CMS like WordPress, Joomla, Drupal, and Magento.
- Worked as UI developer programming interfaces implementing SPA with Angular.
- · Created static pages programming with Astro.
- · Worked in UI/UX design for different kinds of projects.
- Created branding for small businesses designing logos with the 'How to use your brand' manual. Worked with the brand's marketing of these businesses, as well.
- Worked as illustrator creating characters, backgrounds, or drawing different poses for characters created by other illustrators.